https://www.utah.edu/privacy/

Skip to content
Search this Site:
Powered by
Search U of U Campus:
Privacy Statement
The University of Utah has created this statement to demonstrate our firm commitment
to your privacy. This document explains how we gather, use, and protect your information.
We Don't Sell Your Contact Information
While using this site, you may choose to submit personal information through email
or online forms. We will use this information to process your requests. But we will
not intentionally sell, share, or distribute your personal information to third parties,
except as required by law or university policy.
EU General Data Protection Regulation
Please be aware of the University’s GDPR Privacy Notice that supplements this Privacy
Statement. The GDPR Privacy Notice applies generally to the provision of personal
information by individuals in the European Economic Area. The GDPR Privacy Notice
explains how we meet our obligations under the European Union General Data Protection
Regulation with respect to such information. The GDPR Privacy Notice can be found
at https://www.utah.edu/privacy/gdpr.php.
Statistical Logs Kept
The University uses reporting programs to collect data about visitor traffic to our
site. We do not attempt to personally identify visitors. Instead we collect data to
analyze in aggregate to determine trends and improve our sites. Here are some examples
of the types of data we routinely collect:
Cookies Used to Preserve Data
Some U sites require the use of cookies (bits of data passed by your browser to our
site). For instance, the My.Utah.edu portal uses cookies (active only during your
session) to remember password and menu settings. You are not required to use My.Utah.edu;
this tool is provided for your convenience. If you prefer not to receive cookies,
you can turn them off in your browser or set your browser to ask you before accepting
new cookies.
Security Programs Running
We have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to
safeguard and help prevent unauthorized access, to assist in maintaining data security,
and to assist in correctly using the information we collect online. We do not intentionally
release personal information gleaned from these programs to others, except as required
by law.
Security Precautions You Should Take
Although we make every effort to secure our networks, the University cannot guarantee
privacy of online communications. Use discretion in providing information in online
classes, chatrooms, or other open forums on the Web. If you use My.Utah.edu to access
personal records, be sure to "lock up" when you leave by exiting the site AND closing
your browser. Otherwise, the next person to use the computer may see your information.
Alternate Ways to Submit Information
You have a choice about whether to provide personal information online. For other
options, contact the site manager and learn how you can provide information by phone,
mail, fax or in person.
Other Sites Have Different Policies
This site contains links to other independently managed U sites. Some may use information
for purposes other than stated above; be sure to read their separate privacy statements.
U sites also contain links to sites outside the university; these sites may have their
own privacy statement--or none at all. We urge you to exercise caution when providing
personal data to any site. Check their policies and contact them if you have questions.
Protecting Children's Privacy
We encourage parents to explore our website with their children. If we learn that
a child under age 13 has provided personally identifiable information to our sites,
we will promptly remove this from our files. For more on children's privacy rights,
read about the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act at the FTC's website.
Changing Your Information
Here's how to review or change your personal profile information (address, home phone,
e-mail):
On the Web – Log in to the Campus Information Services and click your address, phone, or email to edit.
In Person – Visit Registration Service Window #13 on the 2nd floor of the Student Services Building.
By Phone – Call the Registration Division (801) 581-8969.
Related Policies
Policies & Procedures 1-12 U Institutional Data Management Policy
Policies & Procedures 1-15 U Information Resources Policy
Policies & Procedures 1-16 U World Wide Web Resources Policy
IT Policies and Procedures
Health Information Privacy
The University, and those who work, teach, and learn here, value the privacy of the
health information you provide us. The Information Security and Privacy Office website explains how we handle the personal information that you share with us as
a patient, health/benefits plan member, or participant in a research study. The website
also provides information explaining the rights you have regarding that information
and how to exercise those rights. We provide the notices to make you aware of these
practices and to comply with the law, including the Health Insurance Portability and
Accountability Act (HIPAA) of 1996.
University policies are subject to change. We encourage you to check back for updates
from time to time. If you have additional questions about this privacy statement,
we invite you to contact:
University Webmaster 101 South Wasatch Drive #215 Salt Lake City, UT 84112 (801) 585-7320webmaster@utah.edu
Last Updated: 6/4/18
Effective Date: 10/24/03
webmaster@utah.edu
Last Updated: 9/30/20
